limecrime.com 2019-12-11

# Privacy Policy | Vegan & Cruelty Free Makeup - Lime Crime

PRIVACY POLICY

Lime Crime (“Lime Crime,” “we,” “us,” “our”) (with the help of our lawyers) created this policy to let you know what we do when you tell us stuff about yourself. We know that it seems like nothing is private anymore, but we take this stuff seriously and want to be sure you know what we are up to.

This Policy was last updated on June 3, 2019. This Site is operated in the United States. If you are located in the European Union, Canada or elsewhere outside of the United States, please be aware that any information you provide to us will be collected in or transferred to the United States. Unless otherwise noted, all data described by this policy is stored and processed in the United States.

Lime Crime understands that the privacy of your personal information is important to you, so we have established privacy policies and practices. This notice explains how your data will be used, shared, or otherwise handled by Lime Crime. By visiting limecrimemakeup.com and/or limecrime.com (the “Site”), you agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time. Accordingly, you should check the date of this policy and review any changes since the last posted version. If at any time, you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please cease use of the Site. Your continued use of our Site constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy. The Site is owned and operated by Lime Crime Inc.

How We Get Your Information and What We Do With It

We have to get to know you a little before we take things to the next level. Personal information may be requested and collected when you use our Site, such as upon registration with Lime Crime, when placing an order, when contacting us via phone or email, when interacting with customer support, when joining our email list, or when you slide into our DMs. The personal information we collect includes your user name, password, phone number, email address, mailing address, and payment information. This information will be used to fulfill your orders, process your transactions, facilitate your use of our website(s), respond to your requests, assist you with future shopping, and improve the Site, all of which we have a legitimate interest in.

We also collect non-personal information, such as your IP address and the site that referred you to ours. This assists us in aggregating data in regards to visitor preferences, such as how many users visited a specific page on our site.

We don’t want to be that annoying “friend” that keeps bothering you after you’ve ghosted. But if you give us permission, we may notify you of special promotions, new products or services, or other information that may interest you using the contact information you provide. We also have some pretty cool friends so if you give us permission to share your information with third parties, as described below, you may also receive notifications of special promotions, new products, or additional services from our third-party associates. If you would like to withdraw your consent to receive marketing messages, please send your request to [info@limecrimemakeup.com](mailto:info@limecrimemakeup.com) or utilize the unsubscribe link contained in any marketing email message.

Winner, winner, chicken (or vegan chicken) dinner! In the event Lime Crime conducts an online promotion, contest, or sweepstakes (collectively, a “Promotion”), information we collect will be used consistent with the terms and conditions outlined in the promotion guidelines or rules, which may include a reference to this Policy. You can elect to provide permission for Lime Crime to use the email address and/or telephone number you provide when entering a Promotion for sending you marketing messages. However, you are only required to provide such permission in order to participate in a Promotion if it is necessary for the running of the promotion. For instance, if we request your email address or your social media handle because it is used to notify you if you’ve won and/or to send your prize, and you do not want to provide it, you will not be able to participate in the Promotion. Information you provide us will be used to administer the promotion. If you have not opted in to receive further communications about upcoming promotions, your identifying data will be retained only for as long as it is necessary to administer the Promotion and legally comply with our obligations that extend from your participation, including prize awarding, reporting obligations, and other legitimate matters.

If you would like to revoke your consent to receiving commercial messages you have previously opted in to receive as the result of a Promotion, you can use he unsubscribe link in any marketing message. Don’t worry, you won’t hurt our feelings (ok, maybe a little, but we’ll get over it). If you have previously provided express written consent to receive commercial text promotions, you can reply “STOP” to any marketing text message you receive. You may also send an e-mail to [info@limecrimemakeup.com](mailto:info@limecrimemakeup.com) that contains the email address or phone number you wish to revoke consent for marketing messages. Please note that your inclusion of your mobile number in an order is consent to allow Lime Crime to send you non-marketing messages about your order or account.

Information We May Disclose or Share

We do not disclose, share, rent or sell your personal information to parties not associated with fulfilling your order without your consent unless sharing this information is necessary to provide you with Lime Crime products or is required by law. We consider your personal information a vital part of our relationship with you and your interaction with us and our Site. We may share your personal data: (1) with service providers or contractors who process on behalf of Lime Crime to perform certain business-related functions, such as backup and recovery services, business application services, database and analytics services, and/or bank merchant services to process or fulfill orders; (2) in connection with the sale, assignment, or other transfer of the business of this Site to which the information relates; and/or (3) to respond to law enforcement requests or where required by applicable laws, court orders, or government regulations all of which we have a legitimate interest in doing. Our contracts with these third party processors require them to comply with the terms and the intent of this privacy policy, and to make commercially reasonable efforts to safeguard your information.

The collection, use, and disclosure of information described by this Privacy Policy may involve a transfer of the information to jurisdictions located outside your country of residence that may not have equivalent laws and rules regarding personal data.

Data Retention

You have the right to access, modify, and/or delete your personal data that is held by Lime Crime. To access, modify, and/or delete your personal data, please contact us at [info@limecrimemakeup.com](mailto:info@limecrimemakeup.com). However, if Lime Crime must retain certain personal data for legitimate business purposes, such as to comply with legal requirements or in connection with an order, we will not delete your information until it is no longer required.

Upon your request we will send you a copy of all of your personal data that we hold, though we reserve the right to charge a processing fee for the reasonable time and expenses required to prepare and send the data to you.

We keep your information only for as long as we have a legitimate business purpose, and only that information required for the particular purpose for which you provided it. We will retain your personal information while you have an active relationship with Lime Crime, including if you have subscribed to a newsletter or other commercial/marketing content from us, have visited the site while logged in, have ordered a product, participated in a promotion, or have affirmatively made requests of us that we, or our data processors, are fulfilling. We will maintain your information for ninety days after that relationship ends, unless you request that we delete your information prior to the expiration of that period, which you may do at any time following the instructions here. Except as required under the law, your request will be honored within thirty days. If Lime Crime determines that it no longer requires your information for the purposes set forth above, including any legal purposes, it will delete your information.

C is for Cookies

A cookie is a small, delicious data file that is automatically saved on your computer's hard drive when you visit a website. Cookies may contain information used to record the websites you visit and/or chocolate chips, but cookies do not contain any personally identifiable information such as your name, address, or credit card information (though we can’t speak for the personalized birthday cookies your grandmother baked you). Lime Crime uses cookies to give you a personalized enhanced shopping experience. If you have signed up with Lime Crime, cookies allow our website to recognize you when you return and give you access to your personal account options. Cookies also let our website remember the contents of your Shopping Cart, allowing you to place orders more easily. We may also use cookies to keep track of the ways in which customers find us and navigate through our website. This information will be used internally to help us determine where improvements can be made to our online store.

Most browsers are by default set up to accept cookies and are used by the majority of websites on the Internet. However, if you prefer not to allow our Site to place cookies, you can configure your browser to reject our cookies (sad face). Please note that some aspects of our Site will not function correctly (or at all, in some cases) if you disable cookies.

Examples of types of cookies we use are those that: retain category info on a page, allow us to display pages more quickly, identify your preferred currency, store an encrypted version of your customer ID with the store, store a link to information about your cart and viewing history, or store your preferred language and products you recently viewed.

Links to Other Websites

There may be links to other websites from our Site. Lime Crime does not control any third-party websites and we are not responsible for how these sites use personal information. We encourage you to become familiar with the privacy practices of any linked site when you visit it.

Security

This Site takes reasonable steps to protect your personal data as you transmit it to our Site and to protect such information from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. You should keep in mind that no Internet transmission is ever completely secure or error-free. In particular, e-mail sent to or from this Site may not be secure. We implement a secure processing server on our Site when collecting information to ensure a high level of security for your personal information. Once we receive your personal information, we maintain commercially reasonable physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect it. If a data breach occurs, we will notify you and the proper EEA authority (if required) within 72 hours (if reasonably feasible). If we are unable to notify the proper EEA authority within 72 hours, our notice will be accompanied by reasons for the delay.

Children's Privacy

The Site is a general audience website, intended for adult use. We do not market to, and do not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from, children under sixteen (16) years of age. Children should always get permission from their parents before sending any personal information about themselves (such as their names, email addresses, and phone numbers) over the Internet, to us or to anyone else. We encourage you to become involved in your children's online experience, and to share your knowledge and experience with your young ones. If you’re under 16, please do not register for any of our services or provide us with any personally identifying information (such as your name, email address or phone number). Please contact our customer service department if you are aware of any personal information supplied to the Site by a child under the age of sixteen (16).

Do-Not-Track Signal

Because the do-not track signal does not often reflect the preference of our consumers, our website does not respond to it. Users may, however, elect not to receive marketing messages and/or have certain cookies placed on their browser, as discussed earlier in this Policy.

How to Contact Us

If you have any questions, comments, requests, cool stories, random thoughts, or concerns related to this Privacy Policy or the information practices of this Site, please contact us at [info@limecrimemakeup.com](mailto:info@limecrimemakeup.com).

We Got Beef?

If you have tried to work it out with us and you feel like you aren’t being heard or your issues aren’t being adequately resolved, please send a message to [privacyproblems@limecrimemakeup.com](mailto:privacyproblems@limecrimemakeup.com) and we will be sure to squash whatever beef you have (i.e., we will do whatever we reasonably can to make things right with you).

Lime Crime App Privacy Policy

Lime Crime is the operator of the Lime Crime AR App. This policy informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use and disclosure of Personal Information of users of the app.

Lime Crime App - Social Media Sharing

This app allows you to share predefined image(s) from this app to social media apps and services that are already on your device. These images do not identify you the user, and are the same for all users. However, sharing the image (and any commentary that you supply) will identify you as a user of this app to others on social media.

Lime Crime App - Use of Camera

This app utilizes the video camera on your device. We do not use the camera images for any purpose other than image recognition and registration for the AR functionality. No images from the video camera are captured or stored or transmitted by this app.

Lime Crime App - Analytics Data

We periodically send data from this app to an analytics service in order to understand how users are using this app and to improve it. This data is anonymized and used in aggregate, meaning that we do not collect any information of a personal nature about users. We do use the analytics service to track, collect or upload any data that could be used to personally identify an individual.

Lime Crime App - Contact Us

If you have any questions about this privacy policy, please contact us at: Customercare@limecrime.com
